<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An act for taking of the accompts belonging to the Navy &amp; Customs. Die Mercurii, 8 Augusti, 1649. Ordered by the Commons assembled in Parliament, that this Act be forthwith printed and published. Hen: Scobell, Cleric. Parliment'.</title>
            <title>Laws, etc.</title>
            <author>England and Wales.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1649</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 8 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 4 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A74331</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E1060_53</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R208668</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99867596</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99867596</idno>
            <idno type="VID">169036</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A74331)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 169036)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 157:E1060[53])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An act for taking of the accompts belonging to the Navy &amp; Customs. Die Mercurii, 8 Augusti, 1649. Ordered by the Commons assembled in Parliament, that this Act be forthwith printed and published. Hen: Scobell, Cleric. Parliment'.</title>
                  <title>Laws, etc.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>p. [2], 435-439, [i.e. 7] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed for Edward Husband, printer to the Parliament of England, and are to be sold at his shop in Fleetstreet, at the sign of the Golden-Dragon, near the Inner-Temple,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1649.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signatures: 4F⁴. Also issued as part of a through-paged set with a table for the entire set added.</note>
                  <note>On 4F2r: last word of first line of text: "of"; first word of line below initial: "ment"; last word of last full line: "way:".</note>
                  <note>Ornament on t.p.; initial letter; part of text in black letter.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Parliament. --  Committee of the Navy --  Appropriations and expenditures --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>England and Wales. --  Commissioners of Customs --  Accounting --  Law and legislation --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Customs administration --  Great Britain --  Law and legislation --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Admiralty --  Great Britain --  Accounting --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-09</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:169036:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>AN ACT For taking of the ACCOMPTS Belonging to the Navy &amp; Cuſtoms.</p>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>seal of the Commonwealth</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>Die Mercurii, 8 Auguſti, 1649.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>ORdered by the Commons aſſembled in Parliament, That this Act be forthwith printed and publiſhed.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Hen: Scobell, Cleric. Parliament'.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for <hi>Edward Huſband,</hi> Printer to the Parliament of <hi>England,</hi> and are to be ſold at his Shop in Fleetſtreet, at the Sign of the Golden-Dragon, near the Inner-Temple, 1649.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:169036:2"/>
            <pb n="435" facs="tcp:169036:2"/>
            <head>AN ACT For taking of the ACCOMPTS Belonging to the Navy &amp; Cuſtoms.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">V</seg>VHereas the Receipts of the Cuſtoms &amp; Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidy riſing upon Goods and Merchandize Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported and Imported, and other Revenues appointed for y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenance of the Navy, having been by ſeveral Acts and Ordinances of this preſent Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, committed to the care and management of ſeveral perſons as Commiſsioners and Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lectors thereof; whoſe Accompts, as alſo the Accompts of the Collectors for Prize-Goods, the Treaſurer and Victuallers for the Navy, the Lieutenant and other Officers of the Ord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance, and ſeveral other Officers relating to the Service of the Navy, and the Revenues, Stores and Proviſions thereof, do for the moſt part of them remain unperfected, &amp; are like ſtill ſo to do, if ſome ſpeedy and effectual courſe be not taken for diſpatch thereof in a ſetled and orderly way:
<pb n="436" facs="tcp:169036:3"/> For remedy whereof, and to the end the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monwealth may receive ſatisfaction concerning the Iſſuings and Disburſements of the ſaid Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceipts and Revenues; and that the perſons truſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed therein that have or ſhall faithfully diſcharge the truſt to them reſpectively committed, may be thereof fully acquitted and diſcharged; and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trarywiſe, thoſe that have not, nor ſhall diſcharge their truſt therein may be duly proceeded againſt: Be it therefore Enacted by this preſent Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, and by the authority thereof, That all and every perſon or perſons who ſince the ſit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting of this preſent Parliament, have been, or at any time hereafter ſhall be by Parliament appointed Commiſsioners and Collectors of the Cuſtoms, Subſidies, and other Revenues within <hi>England</hi> and <hi>Wales,</hi> and the Town and Port of <hi>Berwick,</hi> Collectors for Prize-Goods, Treaſurer and Victuallers for the Navy, Lieu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenant, or any other Officers of the Ordnance, and all other Officers and perſons whatſoever, relating to the Service of the Navy, or any the Receipts thereunto ſet apart or aſsigned, and the Stores and proviſions thereof, that have not as yet accompted, or having begun their Accompts, ſhall not at the time of the paſsing of this preſent Act, have perfected the ſame, ſhall and are hereby required forthwith to ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compt, and ſo from time to time for the future, before the Auditors of the Preſts that now are, which ſhall be appointed by authority of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, for all ſuch ſum and ſums of Money, Ammunition or other Stores or proviſions be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longing to the Navy, Prize-Goods, or other Wares or Merchandize, or other things what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever, belonging to the Commonwealth, by them and every of them reſpectively received or
<pb n="437" facs="tcp:169036:3"/> collected, or to their reſpective charge, care or truſt committed, or come unto their hands; and of their Disburſements, Payments, Iſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuings and Diſpoſitions thereof reſpectively, according to the Warrants, Vouchers and Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charges in that behalf appointed by authority and direction of Parliament. And for the bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter enabling the ſaid Auditors to proceed in the taking and auditing of the ſaid accompts, and to charge or ſurcharge all and every the ſaid perſons by this Act accomptable with ſuch ſums of money, and other proviſions, ſtores and other goods, for which by the reſpective truſts to them committed as aforeſaid, they ſtand accomptable to the Commonwealth<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Be it hereby further En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted and Ordained, That the Committee here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tofore authorized by Parliament for taking the general Accompts of the Kingdom, their De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puties, Subcommittee, Regiſters and Clerks, the Remembrancers and Clerks of the Exche<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quer, all Cuſtomers, Comptrollers, Collectors and other Officers for the Cuſtoms, and all Cheque-Officers and Comptrollers upon any the Receipts, Collections, Proviſions, Stores and other Goods aforeſaid; as alſo all Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners, Subcommiſsioners, Collectors, Audi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors or Comptroller of the Excize, ſeperated and diſtinguiſhed for the ſervice of the Navy, do forth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with, and from time to time deliver unto the ſaid Auditors of the Preſts, all Books of Accompts, Blank Books, Inventories, Appriſements, Books of Cheque and Comptrol, and all other Writings whatſoever, relating to the premiſes, as remain in their cuſtody, whereby the ſaid Auditors of the Preſts may be enabled to charge the accompts of the ſaid ſeveral perſons by this Act accomptable reſpectively, with ſuch ſum
<pb n="438" facs="tcp:169036:4"/> and ſums of money, proviſions, ſtores, and other goods, as they and every of them ought juſtly to be charged with, and for which they ſtand ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>comptable to the Commonwealth. And be it hereby further Enacted and Ordained by the au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority aforeſaid, That the ſaid Accompts ſo taken and audited, and hereafter to be taken and audited by the ſaid Auditors of the Preſts, ſhall be declared before the Barons of the Court of the publique Exchequer, in ſuch way and maner as formerly they uſed to be declared be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Lord Treaſurer, or Commiſsioners for the Treaſury for the time being, Chancellor and Barons of the Exchequer; and when declared, they ſhall be by the ſaid Auditors of the Preſts tranſmitted to the Clerk of the Pipe, to be by him ingroſſed upon the great Roll of the Pipe, or Roll of Forraign Accompts, according to the uſual courſe and cuſtom of the Exchequer; and the Clerk of the Pipe is hereby authorized and required to give ſuch Diſcharges and <hi>Quietus eſt</hi> to all the ſaid Accomptants that ſhall finiſh and perfect their Accompts, to charge the ſupers de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pending upon any of the ſaid Accompts, and to do and perform all other thing and things con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning the ſame, as hath been heretofore uſually done in the like kinde, according to the ancient courſe and cuſtom of the ſaid Court of the pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lique Exchequer; and if it ſhall happen that any the ſaid perſon or perſons, or the Executors, Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſtrators or Aſſigns of any ſuch perſon or perſons that ought to accompt as aforeſaid, ſhall not enter upon their reſpective accompts before the ſaid Auditors of the Preſts, and pay in all the moneys in their hands unto the Treaſurer of the Navy, or having entred upon the ſame, ſhall not perfect the ſame, That then ſuch pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceedings
<pb n="439" facs="tcp:169036:4"/> ſhall be had againſt all ſuch perſon or perſons aforeſaid, as heretofore hath been accu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomed, according to the ancient courſe and cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtom of the Exchequer. Provided always, That this Act or any thing therein contained, ſhall not extend to the hindring of any of the aforeſaid per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons from pleading to their ſeveral charges, where there may be juſt matter of plea, but that the ſame courſe ſhall be continued therein, as heretofore hath been uſed, according to the ancient courſe and cuſtom of the ſaid Court of the publique Exchequer.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <opener>
               <dateline>
                  <date>
                     <hi>Die Mercurii,</hi> 8 <hi>Auguſti,</hi> 1649.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>ORdered by the Commons in Parliament aſſembled, That this Act be forthwith printed and publiſhed.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Hen: Scobell, Cleric. Parliament'.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
